搞毛呀
What the hell?
紧急情况预防演习
Emergency preparedness drill.
-别啊  开玩笑吧  -你懂的
- Oh, no, come on! - Yeah, you know how it works.
每三个月一次  保持警惕
Once a quarter, keep our readiness up.
快起床吧  瞌睡虫
Now, rise and shine, sleepy head.
城里半数  死翘翘
Half the town is probably dead.
我一定要给我的门弄个锁
I have to get a lock for my door.
我觉得你会喜欢今晚的演习
I think you'll like the drill tonight.
我在寓教于乐方面花了不少心思
I've tried to make it fun.
每张卡片上都详细介绍了一个场景
Each of these cards contains a detailed scenario
每个场景都代表一种可能的末日级灾难
of a possible apocalyptic event.
囊括了从森林大火
Everything from wild fires
到加拿大的突然入侵
to a surprise invasion by Canada.
选个灾难吧  随便哪个都行
Pick a catastrophe, any catastrophe.
谢尔顿  加拿大攻不到加州的
Sheldon, Canada is not going to invade California.
真的吗  你真觉得华盛顿州和俄勒冈州的
Yeah, really? You think those hippies
那帮脓包能挡得住加拿大人吗
in Washington and Oregon can stop them?
好吧
Fine.
好嘞
All righty!
"一场8.2级的地震摧毁了帕萨迪纳市
"An 8.2 magnitude earthquake devastates Pasadena,
高楼大厦被夷为平地
reducing mighty edifices to dust,
火灾在全城蔓延
engulfing the city in flames.
街道上血流成河
The streets flow with blood
遍地伤者哀嚎不已"
and echo with the cries of the wounded."
选得好啊
Oh, excellent choice.
快戴上安全帽  穿上安全背心
Now, put on your hardhat and safety vest.
真有意思啊
Oh, fun.
我又得穿得像"村民"组合里的某位成员一样
I get to spend another night in front of our apartment
70年代的经典男子演唱组合
其中一位经常扮成建筑工人
整晚上傻站在楼前了
dressed like one of the Village People.
你每三个月就得这么吐一次槽
You make that joke every three months.
可我还是没看出槽点
I still don't get it.
莱纳德  等下
Leonard... wait.
你在干嘛呢
What are you doing?
我也不知道  怎么了
I don't know, what am I doing?
你看看周围
Look around you--
到处都是可能存在的碎玻璃
there's hypothetical broken glass everywhere.
不是吧  不带上足部矫形器就去最终决战吗
Really? You're going to face Armageddon without your orthotics?
你自己看着办
Your choice.
可能的余震来了
Uh-oh, hypothetical aftershock!
所以要戴安全帽嘛
And that's why we wear hardhats.
你看这个  来自宇航局的新闻
Check it out-- press release from NASA.
"第31批考察队将于今年春天
"Expedition 31 will launch this spring
前往国际空间站
to the International Space Station.
队员包括中校"汤包"汤姆·约翰逊
Crew members will include Commander Tom 'Tombo' Johnson,
宇航员"超新星"迈克·诺瓦里克
Astronaut Mike 'Supernova' Novacelik
和随行专家霍华德·沃罗威茨"
and Payload Specialist Howard Wolowitz."
这条肯定要上我的犹太教堂日报
This is going right into my synagogue's newsletter.
哥们儿  如果你打算当宇航员的话
Dude, if you're going to be an astronaut,
你得取个霸气的绰号啊
you need to pick a cool nickname.
才不用我来取呢
I don't get to pick it.
别人会给我取的
The other guys have to give it to me.
如果我有绰号的话  肯定是"劲爆巧克力"
Oh. If I had one, it would be "Brown Dynamite."
你在听我说话吗
Are you not listening to me?
绰号只能是别人帮你取
The other astronauts have to give you your nickname.
你没在看着我吗
Are you not looking at me?
我就是"劲爆巧克力"
I am Brown Dynamite.
你为啥往咖啡里加了六包糖
Why do you put six sugars in your coffee?
因为食堂里不提供
Because the cafeteria doesn't offer
小包的甲基苯丙胺[可合成兴奋剂]
little packets of methamphetamine.
昨晚是紧急事件演习对吧
Emergency drill night last night, huh?
-对啊  -你怎么样
- Uh-huh. - How'd you do?
我来告诉你他怎么样
I'll tell you exactly how he did.
"是否准备充分：差强人意
"Readiness: unsatisfactory.
是否听从指挥：刚愎自用
Follows direction: barely.
是否带有情绪：牢骚略多
Attitude: a little too much.
综上所述
Overall:
他不仅会在灾难中死得很惨
not only will he probably die in a fiery inferno,
他旷日持久的牢骚会毁掉别人的好心情"
his incessant whining would most certainly spoil everyone else's day."
我太累了  脑子都不转了
You know what, I'm so tired, I can't even think straight.
我回去了
I'm going home.
你们哪位愿意待会儿送这位二逼青年回家
Will one of you guys give this nutbag a ride back later?
你不能回去
You can't go home.
你四点钟还得送我去看牙医
You have to take me to the dentist at 4:00.
你就不能自己坐公交去吗
Oh... can't you take the bus to the dentist?
我当然能  问题是回来的时候
Of course I can. It's coming back,
有麻醉剂的后续作用
under the residual effects of the anesthesia,
这才是麻烦的地方
that's the problem.
两年前
Two years ago,
在一次全面牙龈清洗过后  我以为我上了公交车
after a deep gum cleaning, I thought I got on a bus
醒来却发现自己在墨西哥烈酒游行团车上
but somehow wound up on a booze cruise to Mexico.
你洗个牙龈都得打麻药啊
They put you under for a cleaning?
没办法  我急起来会咬人
Yeah, they have to-- I'm a biter.
我不管了  谢尔顿  我累得不行了
Whatever, Sheldon. I'm exhausted.
我没法带你去看牙医了
I'm not taking you to the dentist.
不行啊  哥们儿
Wrong, sir.
不行  根据室友协议的第37条B款
Wrong. Under Section 37-B of the Roommate Agreement--
"杂项职责"  你有义务
"Miscellaneous Duties"-- you are obligated
带我去看牙医
to take me to the dentist.
看到了吧  就在"为可能坏掉的乳制品
See? It's right here after "providing a confirmation sniff
提供气味确认"这条的后面
on questionable dairy products."
你挺好  我受够了室友协议
You know what, I am sick of the Roommate Agreement.
傻透了
It's ridiculous.
我是你的室友  不是你的司机
I'm your roommate, not your chauffeur.
我昨天本来有别的事情要做
You know, I had better things to do yesterday
结果却得载你去加登格罗夫的一家
than drive you all the way to the "good" model train store
"不错"火车模型店  就因为帕萨迪纳的那家
in Garden Grove because the one in Pasadena
"服务态度太傲慢了"
has gotten "too big for its britches."
确实很傲慢
Well, it has.
你去问问啊
Ask anybody.
我才不管呢  我受够了
I don't care. I'm done.
等下
Hold on.
你是说你想使用第209条吗
Are you saying that you want to invoke Clause 209?
我不知道那条是啥
I don't know what that is,
但如果那条能让我回家睡觉的话  我就用
but if it means I can go home and sleep, then yes.
你先想清楚
Think carefully here.
第209条会终止我们的友谊
Clause 209 suspends our friendship,
并解除室友协议  仅剩一些基本条款
and strips down the Roommate Agreement to its bare essentials.
我们对彼此的义务仅限于交房租  共用生活设施
Our responsibilities toward each other would only be rent, utilities
和在大厅里见面时出于认识
and a perfunctory chin jut of recognition
而冷漠地抬个头
as we pass in the hall.
哟
'Sup?
我要在哪签名
Where do I sign?
就这里
Right here.
用手指即可
Use your finger.
-签好了  -好的  到此结束
- There. Done. - All right. That's it.
从此你走你的阳关道
We are now no longer companions,
我过我的独木桥
boon or otherwise.
我们现在连点头之交都不是
We are not merely acquaintances.
修改一下《玩具总动员》的金句
To amend the words of Toy Story--
源自《玩具总动员》的主题曲
"You've got a friend in me[我是你的好朋友]"
"我不是你的好朋友"
"You have not got a friend in me."
我要回家小睡了
I'm gonna go home and take a nap.
跟在乎的人说去吧
Yeah, well, tell it to someone who cares.
今天我接到个激动人心的宇航局消息
I got pretty exciting NASA news today.
下周我就要飞去休斯顿
Next week I fly to Houston
进行空间定向能力和零重力排便训练
for orientation and zero-gravity elimination drills.
那是指什么
What does that mean?
他要去学习如何在太空里拉屎
He's gonna learn to poop in space.
打开分离舱门  哈尔
Open the pod bay doors, HAL.
或许你的绰号才应该叫"劲爆屎颗粒"
Maybe your nickname should be "Brown Dynamite."
朋友们好啊
Hello, dear friends.
还有霍夫斯塔德博士
And Dr. Hofstadter.
哟
'Sup?
不好意思
My apologies.
我本来可以早点回来
I would've been here sooner,
可那巴士老是停下来载客
but the bus kept stopping for other people to get on it.
我给你留了个饺子
I saved you a dumpling.
你对我的关心真叫人感动
Oh, your concern for me is touching.
等你明天载我去看牙医
It will serve you well
我再好好报答你
when you take me to the dentist tomorrow.
对不起  谢尔顿  我很忙
I'm sorry, Sheldon, I'm busy.
我正忙着做瘾疾研究
I'm right in the middle of my addiction study.
整个实验室都是酗酒的猴子
I've got a lab full of alcoholic monkeys,
明天正好要让它们改喝无酒精啤酒
and tomorrow's the day we switch them to O'Doul's.
你是我的女朋友
You're my girlfriend
居然不迎合我的每一个需求
and you're not going to cater to my every need?
哎  爱情的魔力都到哪里去了
Oh, where'd the magic go?
谢尔顿  女朋友不是这么用的
Sheldon, that's not what girlfriends are for.
不过  她们真正的用处你也用不到
Although, you don't use them for what they're for,
所以我也不知道了
so what do I know?
霍华德就不会叫我帮他买东西
Howard doesn't make me do his shopping
送他去看牙医
or take him to the dentist
帮他拿干洗的衣服  对吧
or pick up his dry cleaning, right?
那当然
Absolutely.
不过等我妈行动不便了  就由你顶上
But when Ma's hips give out, you're up, kid.
既然艾米太忙  就给你们一个
Well, if Amy's too busy, that gives the rest of you
让我生活更轻松的机会吧
an opportunity to make my life easier,
我保证带我去的人  能在我那本暂命名为
thus assuring yourselves a footnote in my memoirs,
《不客气  凡夫俗子》的回忆录里留一个注脚
tentatively entitled You're Welcome, Mankind.
好了
All right, then,
听到你想接的任务时就吼一声
just shout when you hear the task you want to undertake.
看牙医
Uh, dentist.
没事  我们回头再说这个
Okay, w-we can circle back to that one.
谁想在星期三早上
Um, well, who wants to take me Wednesday morning
带我去换绅士鞋的鞋跟
to get new heels put on my dress shoes?
谁想去
Anyone?
看来这个没人喜欢
Oh. That one had hoot written all over it.
好吧  去看皮肤科医生
Um, all right, uh, dermatologist.
过敏症医生
Allergist.
足科医生
Podiatrist.
超级理发师[理发店]
Supercuts?
好吧  还有个好玩的
Okay, okay, here's a fun one.
我要买个新相框
Um, I need a new picture frame
而且我想去吃瑞典肉丸
and I have a hankering for Swedish meatballs.
谁想那天陪我去宜家[瑞典家居品牌]
Who wants to spend the day with me at IKEA?
-他们的肉丸很好吃  -你说什么
- Their meatballs are pretty good.  - What's that?
没有  我什么都没说
Nothing, nothing.
你好  斯图尔德
Hello, Stuart.
你好  谢尔顿
Oh, hey, Sheldon.
今天想买什么呀
Can I help you find something today?
不  不
No, no.
我刚刚坐在家里
I was just sitting at home
想着要能跟我的第九号喜欢人物聊聊
thinking about how it might be nice to catch up
该是多好的事啊
with my ninth favorite person.
第九号
Ninth?
你刚上升一名次哦
You moved up one.
我的索马里笔友被海盗绑架了
My pen pal in Somalia was kidnapped by pirates.
你最近好吗
So, uh... how are you?
不太好
Uh... not so good.
我的心理医生自杀了
My shrink just killed himself and...
还留下纸条说都怪我
blamed me in the note.
好  很好
Great. Great.
那你家人怎么样
So, what's new with your family?
令堂好吗  还健在不
How's your mother? Is she alive?
在
Yeah.
那令尊呢  还健在不
And your father? Alive?
在
Yes.
那祖父母呢  他们还健在不
How about your grandparents, they alive?
不在了
No.
节哀顺变
Oh, I'm so sorry for your loss.
说件开心的事吧
On a cheerier note,
我今天下午预约了去洁牙
I have a teeth-cleaning appointment this afternoon.
要不你送我过去吧  好伙计
What do you say you take me over there, buddy boy?
不好意思  你要我送你去看牙医吗
I'm sorry, you want me to take you to the dentist?
对  我现在承诺不了什么
Yes. Now, I can't make any promises,
但想挤进我第八位好友的候选名单
but that's the sort of thing that gets a fella on the short list
这种事绝对有加分哦
for the number eight friend slot.
谢尔顿  我在工作
Sheldon, I'm working.
我不能带你去看牙医
I can't take you to the dentist.
而且  我必须强调
Also-- and I can't stress this enough--
我不想带你去看牙医
I don't want to take you to the dentist.
在朋友有需要的时候也不帮一把  是吧
Can't help a friend out in a time of need, huh?
我明白你的心理医生为什么要自杀了
I see where your therapist was coming from.
想到了  我们把你的宇航员绰号定为
Ooh, ooh! What about we make your astronaut nickname
霍华德"巴斯"沃罗威茨怎么样
Howard "Buzz" Wolowitz?
不能用"巴斯"
You can't do "Buzz."
"巴斯"已经有人用了
"Buzz" is taken.
巴斯光年又不是真人
Buzz Lightyear is not real.
没错  但我不是这个意思
No, that's not what I'm talking about.
你是说他以为自己是真人的时候吗
Well, are you talking about when he thought he was real?
不是
No.
好吧  那"坠"怎么样
Okay, um... how about "Crash"?
霍华德·坠·沃罗威茨
Howard "Crash" Wolowitz.
好极了  其他宇航员
Yeah, terrific. The other astronauts
肯定会爱死和一个名字
would love to go hurtling through space
带"坠"落的人
with a guy named "Crash."
好吧  让我想想
All right, um, how about...
火箭客怎么样
Oh, how about "Rocket Man"?
这个不赖  霍华德·"火箭客"·沃罗威茨
That's not bad, Howard "Rocket Man" Wolowitz.
是很不错  但我也说了
Yeah, it's great, but I told you,
绰号不是我选的
I don't get to pick my nickname.
是其他宇航员给你起的
It has to come from the other astronauts.
也许有办法让别人想到这个
Maybe there's a way to get them to come up with it.
比如呢
Like how?
我以前试过带着个邓肯溜溜球
Once I tried carrying around a Duncan yo-yo,
希望其他孩子会叫我邓肯
hoping the other kids would start calling me Duncan.
成功了吗
Did it work?
没有  他们最后叫我袜子嘴
No, they ended up calling me Sock Mouth.
因为他们抢走了我的溜溜球
Because they took away my yo-yo
还把他们的袜子塞进我嘴里
and stuffed their socks in my mouth.
好吧  要是我们把"火箭客"做你手机铃声
Okay, uh, what if we make "Rocket Man" your ringtone,
下次你和那些宇航员说话的时候
and the next time you talk to those guys,
我就打电话给你  让他们听到
I'll call you and they'll hear it.
埋下心理暗示的种子
Plant the seed.
这个计划还真不赖
That's actually not a terrible plan.
哥的"劲爆巧克力"外号可不是白叫的
They don't call me "Brown Dynamite" for nothing.
哟
'Sup?
你有没有去看牙医呀
Hey, did you ever make it to the dentist?
没必要了
Not necessary. No.
我找到一项服务  他们会派辆车来你家
I found a service that'll send a van to your house
为你洗牙
for a teeth cleaning.
他们大多为狗服务  不过
Mostly they cater to dogs, but...
接电话的那个人还算思想开放
...the fellow on the phone seemed to have an open mind.
好吧  谢尔顿
All right, Sheldon,
如果你要我开车送你去看牙医
if you need me to take you to the dentist,
我会送你去的
I will take you to the dentist.
这么说你是意识到了
Are you suggesting that you've come to your senses
并且想要重新接受室友协议
and wish to reestablish the mutual benefits that stem
恢复我们之间的互惠互助吗
from full participation in the Roommate Agreement?
当然了
Absolutely.
只要你承认你都三十岁了
If you admit that you're a 30-year-old man
还没法自己一个人独立生活
who's incapable of functioning on his own.
矮油  袜子嘴先生让他下不来台了
Ooh, Sock Mouth's got him on the ropes.
我才不会承认这种事情
I will admit nothing of the sort.
现在我要失陪了
And now if you'll excuse me,
我要打电话给我牙医
I have to call my dentist and see
看他是不是也能帮我洗个头发剪个指甲
if I can also get my hair shampooed and my nails clipped.
太好了  你这里也断电了
Oh, good, your power's out, too.
这算哪门子好
Why is that good?
因为上个月
Because last month,
我给电力公司寄了张星巴克礼品卡
I sent the electric company a Starbucks gift card,
一封道歉信  和一些我穿着胸罩的照片
an apology note, and a few snapshots of me in a bra.
断电了
Power failure.
启动断电应急预案
Implementing power-failure protocol.
你不是在地板上画了夜光逃生路线么
What happened to all your glow- in-the-dark-emergency-exit stuff
怎么没了
you had painted on the floor?
那玩意儿致癌
Oh, that was wildly carcinogenic.
不管怎样
Anyway...
你失去了我互助互惠的友谊
it's too bad you're no longer entitled
真是太不幸了
to the full benefits of my friendship,
因为我刚好为应付这种情况
because I happen to be extremely prepared
做了充分的准备
for such an emergency.
拜托你别借着这个灯光看东西
Please try not to see anything by this light.
这灯光不借外人用
It's not for you.
这只是断电  我肯定马上就恢复了
It's just a blackout; I'm sure the power will be back on soon.
唐纳组织里的某些白痴
And I'm sure some fool in the Donner party
唐纳组织:  美国早期拓荒者组织
拓荒旅途中因遭遇暴雪被困  发生了人吃人的惨剧
也说过雪马上就会停呢
said the snow would stop any day now.
我希望他们先吃了他
I like to think they ate him first.
我公寓里有些蜡烛
You know, I got some candles in my apartment.
蜡烛  现在可是在断电
But candles?! During a blackout?!
你疯了吗  那会有着火的危险
Are you mad? That's a fire hazard.
不  帕萨迪纳水电公司推荐使用
No, Pasadena Water and Power recommends
更安全的荧光棒
the far safer glow stick.
你那玩意也敢叫荧光棒
You call that a glow stick?
这才是荧光棒
That is a glow stick.
来吧  我们走
Come on, let's go.
等等  考虑下这个
Before you go, consider this.
我不但有深循环的海军陆战队电池
Not only do I have a deep-cycle marine battery power source
这能更好地支持
which is more than capable
我们的娱乐活动
of running our entertainment system,
我还有
I also have
一共61集的BBC科幻剧《红矮星号》
all 61 episodes of the BBC series Red Dwarf...
还有《无聊星人》
and Fiddle-Faddle.
都是你的
All yours
只要你愿意恢复室友协议
if you're willing to reinstate the Roommate Agreement.
我家有酒  我们还可以摁泡泡塑料包装
I've got wine at my place and some bubble wrap we could pop.
他会回来的
Oh, he'll be back.
和一个女孩在黑暗里喝酒
Wine and a girl in the dark--
他肯定会无聊死的
he's gonna be bored out of his mind.
敬美酒和泡泡包装
To wine and bubble wrap.
也敬不用看着谢尔顿演示
And to not having to watch Sheldon demonstrate
他怎么用反向渗透机
his reverse osmosis machine
把尿转换成饮用水
that converts urine into drinking water.
知道吗  在女孩子童子军里
You know, in Girl Scouts, Tammie Dineesha said
苔米·戴妮莎说  你用丝袜就可以这么做
you could do that with panty hose.
天啊  那才叫错的离谱
Boy, was she wrong.
不说了  你想来亲热一下吗
Anyway, you want to make out?
我们的关系不是在测试中吗
I thought because our relationship's in a beta test,
我以为你想慢慢来
you wanted to take things slow.
好吧
Okay.
你想慢慢地来亲热吗
Do you want to make out slow?
我可以慢得像是蜗牛在你嘴里爬
I can go so slow it'll be like there's a snail in your mouth.
算你走运  反正现在也没其他事好干
Well, lucky for you, there's nothing else to do right now.
不好意思  莱纳德
Excuse me, Leonard.
你打什么时候开始不敲门的
Since when don't you knock?
这差不多是你唯一的优点了
It's like the only good thing about you.
这可不是讲究社交礼仪的时候  莱纳德
Social niceties have been suspended, Leonard.
现在可是紧急情况
We're in a state of emergency.
整个世界陷入黑暗动乱之中
The world has descended into darkened turmoil.
现在就必须目无法纪  野蛮行事
Lawlessness and savagery are the order of the day.
好吧  什么事
Fine, what is it?
我在做烤棉花糖
I'm making s'mores.
我是想来预先警告你
I wanted to alert you
以免你闻到烤棉花糖的教堂香味
in case you smelled caramelizing marshmallows
会以为是附近的糖果厂着火了
and thought a nearby candy factory was on fire.
烤棉花糖是吧  你厉害
S'mores, huh? Good for you.
要变成"我们"真厉害也行
Yes, or good for us
只要你在这签名
if you sign here
恢复我们原来的室友协议就行了
and reinstate the full Roommate Agreement.
不用了  谢谢  这样就行了
No, thanks. I'm good.
真的吗
Really?
好吧
Huh! Okay.
这样的话  我就自己独享烤棉花糖了
In that case, I will have a s'more by myself.
然后我就会做出更多
And then I'm gonna have s'more.
独立完成
By myself.
别可怜他
No, don't "aw" him.
这一切都是他搞出来的
He brought this all on himself.
但他现在很可怜
But he's sad.
不  他在发疯
No, he's crazy.
有时候发疯看着很可怜
Sometimes crazy looks like sad
这样你才会重新上当
so it'll suck you back in.
他是在想念自己的小伙伴吧
I think he misses his little buddy.
好吧
Fine.
但记住我的话
But mark my words,
咱这场挫败的少年亲热大戏  可还没完
this frustrating, bogus teenage make-out session is not over.
你不是说蜡烛很危险吗
I thought you said candles were dangerous.
这是本生灯
This is a Bunsen burner.
我是科学家  知道自己在做什么
I'm a scientist; I know what I'm doing.
该死
Oh, drat.
我用了一加仑尿液才制出那杯水的
It took me a gallon of urine to make that water.
谢尔顿  咱别做傻事了
Listen, Sheldon, this is stupid.
我们怎么就不能做朋友了
I don't see why we can't be friends.
我是很乐意载你出去
And I'm willing to drive you around
帮你办各种事务的
and help you out with stuff.
我只是不愿意
I just don't want to do it
为了什么傻帽室友协议才这样做
because of some silly Roommate Agreement.
你有何提议
What are you proposing?
我提议咱回到从前那样
That we go back to the way things were.
但在我为你做点事之后
But when I do something for you,
你应该表达出一点感激之情
you show a little appreciation.
你想让我怎么表达
And how would I do that?
你跟我说"谢谢你"
You say "thank you."
每次都要说吗
Every time?
这样不算疯狂
It's not crazy.
我有反对意见
Counter-proposal.
我们恢复之前所有室友协议
We reinstate the full Roommate Agreement
并添加如下附录
with the following addendum:
本着母亲节或父亲节精神
in the spirit of Mother's Day or Father's Day,
每年  我们特别留出一天
once a year, we set aside a day
以赞美你对我生活的所有贡献
to celebrate all your contributions to my life,
不管是你真正的贡献还是想象中的贡献
both actual and imagined by you.
我们可以叫它"莱纳德节"
We could call it Leonard's Day.
这叫法  我喜欢
I kind of like the sound of that.
你当然喜欢
Of course you do.
这可是你的节  就像其他节一样
It's about you, like everything else.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
我膀胱里的尿不够再做一杯水了
I don't think I had it in me to make another glass of water.
-那莱纳德节那天你会把早餐端我床上吗  -不
- So, do I get breakfast in bed on Leonard's Day? - No.
-那天能坐你的位置吗  -不行
- Can I sit in your spot? - No.
-能让我调节下恒温器吗  -不能
Can I control the thermostat? No.
能送我张贺卡吗
Do I get a card?
当然
Of course you get a card.
那可是莱纳德节啊
It's Leonard's Day.
两位  物业经理说
Hey, guys, the building manager said
整幢楼停电的原因是
the reason the power went out is
有人偷偷下去到地下室
someone went down into the basement
把电源总开关给关了
and just pulled the main breaker switch.
真的吗
Really.
你觉得这会是谁做的呀  谢尔顿
Who do you think did that, Sheldon?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
但不管这神秘人是谁
But whoever that mystery man was,
你都该永远感谢他
you should be eternally grateful,
因为没有他  就不会有莱纳德节
for without him, there would be no Leonard's Day.
莱纳德节
Leonard's Day?
不必有压力
Oh, no pressure.
只要送他张小小的贺卡  就行了
Just get him a crummy card, you're good.
好了  测试我的手机铃声
All right, test my ring tone.
-真是首好歌啊  -没错
- That really is a good song. - Oh, yeah.
艾尔顿·约翰封爵可是有原因的
There's a reason he's Sir Elton John.
爵位可不是随便封的
They don't make you a knight
写《走之前叫醒我》这档次的歌就不可能封爵了
for writing "Wake Me Up Before You Go Go."
霍华德  下来吃早餐吗
Howard, are you coming down for breakfast?!
妈  我说过了我跟宇航局有个视讯会议
Ma, I told you I have a video conference with NASA!
别来烦我
I said don't bother me!
好吧  谁敢不听大腕宇航员的话啊
Oh! Listen to Mr. Big Shot Astronaut!
是啊  那你就听我这大腕宇航员的吧
Yes, please listen to Mr. Big Shot Astronaut!
早上好
Hey, good morning.
早  霍华德  多谢为本次会议早起
Hey, Howard, thanks for getting up so early.
全名为Micheal J.Massimino  真正的美国宇航员
在太空写Twitter的第一人
不用  马西米诺博士
No problem, Dr. Massimino.
这里的人叫我马西[英文直译为质量]
The guys here call me Mass.
质量  好酷的外号
Mass! That's a cool nickname.
力等于质量乘以加速度
'Cause force equals mass times acceleration.
没错
Yeah.
其实只是我姓氏"马西米诺"的简称
It's just short for Massimino.
好了  今天早上的计划是谈谈...
Anyway, the plan for this morning is to go over the...
抱歉  我有电话
Sorry. My phone.
那是什么歌  《火箭客》吗
What is that? Is that "Rocket Man"?
对  我的铃声
Yeah, my ring tone.
《火箭客》是我最喜欢的歌
Kind of my favorite song, "Rocket Man."
霍华德
Howard,
你的水果麦圈要泡软啦
your Fruit Loops are getting soggy!
等下再说
Not now!
那是谁
Who's that?
是我妈  抱歉
My mom. Sorry.
没关系  水果麦圈客
No problem... Fruit Loops.